<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>News on Metiri Consult</title>
    <link>https://metiri.dk/news/</link>
    <description>Recent content in News on Metiri Consult</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 05 Oct 2023 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://metiri.dk/news/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Backlog reduction in Tirana</title>
      <link>https://metiri.dk/news/tirana_oct23/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 05 Oct 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://metiri.dk/news/tirana_oct23/</guid>
      <description>From late September to early October I was on a 9-day mission to Tirana.
The project aims to assist the Albanian High Judicial Council (HJC) to better exercise its mandate to monitor court performance, and will in response to a specific request from the HJC focus on the backlog situation in four courts in Tirana. The initiative is part of a justice sector project implemented by East-West Management Institute (EWMI), and is financed by the US Department of State, Bureau of International Narcotics and Law Enforcement Affairs (INL).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Moldova conference</title>
      <link>https://metiri.dk/news/moldova_sep23/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 21 Sep 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://metiri.dk/news/moldova_sep23/</guid>
      <description>On September 20 I participated (online) in the Justice and Anticorruption Reforms Forum in Moldova. The conference was organized by the Legal Resources Centre (LRCM).
In my presentation on court optimization I had the opportunity to reflect upon my previous collaboration with LRCM to analyze the judicial map in Moldova. I also gave a brief demonstration of a software application to compare various judicial map designs.
A recording of the entire conference is available on Youtube.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Uzbekistan report</title>
      <link>https://metiri.dk/news/uzbekistan_jun23/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Jun 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://metiri.dk/news/uzbekistan_jun23/</guid>
      <description>Submitted my analysis of judicial workload and allocation of judges in Uzbekistan to the Supreme Judicial Council.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>JAR-association conference</title>
      <link>https://metiri.dk/news/jara_may23/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 26 May 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://metiri.dk/news/jara_may23/</guid>
      <description>Participated in the inaugural JAR-association congress ‘Innovation in Judicial Systems: Human, Cyber and Beyond’ in Rome.
I presented a paper titled &amp;ldquo;Explaining cross-country differences in the number of judges per capita&amp;rdquo;. Here is the abstract:
It is rather common to focus on the number professional judges per capita when assessing the need for judges in various countries. The EU Rule of Law Report is just one example of this tendency. This simple indicator does however not take into account that the demand for justice in different countries may vary quite a lot because of socio-economic factors.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
